《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我们的兄弟此刻就在渡海
Our brothers are crossing the ocean even now.
哥谭将在鲜血中得到救赎
Gotham will be redeemed in blood.
通过随机杀掉九个人吗
By killing nine random people?
你疯了
You're insane.
受害者并不都是随机的
And not all the victims are random.
哥谭之子
The Son of Gotham.
我要让你说实话
I'm gonna make sure that you are telling the truth.
你敢动我  我叔叔就会宰了你
Touch me, and my uncle will have you gutted.
行了吧
Are we good?
行了
Yes.
布鲁斯
Bruce.
我就从没信过你那套戏码
I never bought your stupid act.
你装作是我的朋友
You pretended to be my friend.
再见了  茜尔薇
Good-bye, Silver.
杀了他
Kill him.
盖勒文在哪
Where's Galavan?!
你想要什么
What do you want?
当然是你的命了
Why, your life, of course.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 辰星晓Reginamoon   盐湖凉开水   Silence   DustD
翻译 木浅   charcie   大K   小酸奶!   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 你是不是饿得慌   校对 草草   总监 草草
伙计们
Hey, guys.
我把硬盘修好了
I fixed the hard drive.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred?
你没事吧
You okay?
喝水吗
Glass of water?
无论怎样  我都不会在文件上签字的
I won't sign those papers, no matter what you do.
我已经放弃了
I'm resigned to that.
你是个非常勇敢的男孩
You're a very brave boy.
我只能通过其他方式得到你的公司了
I'll just have to acquire your company by other means.
我的真名是杜马
My true name is Dumas.
很久以前
And a long time ago,
我的家族曾被你的家族羞辱
my family were dishonored and degraded
贬低
by yours.
我很遗憾  但是...
I'm sorry about that, but...
几世纪以来我们高贵的家族
For centuries our noble clan
过得艰辛卑贱  默默无闻
lived in vile, squalid obscurity.
但我们心怀希望
But we lived in hope.
因为我们的守护圣徒
Because our patron saint
一直说着未来的荣耀之日
spoke of a glorious day to come.
但想迎来这一日
But that day would only come
必须先让哥谭九人
when nine men of Gotham
以及我们死敌最后的子嗣
and the last son of our mortal enemy
被正义之手斩除
are slain by righteous hands.
就是指你  布鲁斯
That's you, Bruce.
你就是最后的子嗣
You're the last son.
停下
Stop that.
高兴点  孩子
Be glad, boy.
你是你家族受膏[成圣]的赎罪者
You're the anointed redeemer of your family.
这七代人以来
For seven generations,
韦恩家族一直身陷于罪恶和腐败之中
the Wayne family has wallowed in vice and corruption.
今晚  在午夜天选之时
So tonight, at the forewarned hour of midnight,
杜马家族将大仇得报
the Dumas will be avenged,
而韦恩家族的罪恶
and the sins of the Wayne family
将以你的血洗刷干净
shall wash away in your blood.
哥谭
第二季  第十一集
该死的
Oh, bloody hell!
*前路黑暗*
*The path is dark*
*遮蔽双眼*
*So dark I cannot see*
*但我不害怕*
*But I will not fear*
*因为我妈妈照顾我*
*For my mother looks over me*
怎么回事
What the hell?
可算醒了
At last.
你感觉怎样呀
How are you feeling?
不太好
Not so good.
尼格玛
Nygma?
说来话长
Long story.
他是我的朋友
He's a friend.
朋友
A friend?
对了  不用谢
You're welcome, by the way.
救你一命什么的  用不着谢我
No thanks needed, saving your life and all.
对了  我是该谢谢你
Yeah, thanks, I guess.
不用  真的
No, really.
我们是朋友嘛
What are friends for?
你被打得不轻啊
You got beat pretty bad.
盖勒文脾气真火爆  是吧
That Galavan is a pistol, isn't he?
没错
Yeah, he is.
你当然可以离开  吉姆
You're free to go, of course, Jim.
尽管你现在是个亡命逃犯
Desperate fugitive from the law, though you be.
但我还是恳请你
But I beg of you,
坐下来想一想吧
sit and consider.
我们因西奥·盖勒文而联系在一起
You and I share a bond in Theo Galavan.
可以说  是有同样的深仇大恨
A passion, if you will.
如果说我们什么时候应该合作
If there was ever a time for us to work together,
那就是现在了
now is that time.
没错  哥哥  这都是你的
Yes, brother, it's all yours.
拜托你笑一笑啊
For God's sakes, smile.
你找到那个管家了吗
Did you find the manservant?
没有
Nope.
你把他丢了
You lost him?
一个老管家能做什么
What can one old butler do?
这不是重点
That's not the point.
重要的是你懒散的态度
The point is your lackadaisical attitude.
我们要筑造一个帝国
We're building an empire here.
紧张了  是吗
Getting nervous, are we?
你的幼稚没那么好笑了
Your childishness is no longer funny.
你得成熟起来了
You need to grow up.
得了  别那么严肃了
Oh, please. Pull the stick out, big shot.
我可是知道你从前的样子
Like I don't know you from way back.
住口
Don't.
没有这些金钱和权力  你算什么
Without all of this wealth and power, what are you?
不过是个可悲的小...
A sad little...
我说  住口
I said don't.
西奥叔叔
Uncle Theo?
亲爱的
Yes, my dear.
有什么事
What is it?
我感冒了
I'm fighting off a cold.
我今晚想早一点睡觉
I was thinking I'd go to bed early tonight,
如果我可以不去...
if it's okay to miss out on...
参加仪式的话
the ceremony?
感冒
A cold?
真的吗
Really?
茜尔薇  我不禁怀疑
I'm beginning to wonder, Silver,
你是不是能胜任今后的工作
if you're cut out for the task ahead of us.
我可以的
I am.
布鲁斯·韦恩击败了你
Bruce Wayne bested you,
而你仍同情他
and yet you still feel for him.
他对你来说应该无足轻重
He should be nothing to you.
是这样的
He is.
他对来说毫无意义
He's nothing to me.
但你也没法眼睁睁看着他死吧
But you can't watch him die, can you?
你心软了  茜尔薇
You're soft, Silver.
你有同情心了
You have compassion.
没有
No.
没有吗
No?
那就试试看吧
Let's see, shall we?
我要考验你一下
I'm going to give you a test.
什么都行
Anything.
让布鲁斯·韦恩再次爱上你
Make Bruce Wayne fall in love with you all over again.
我想看到他死前给你一吻
I want to see him kiss you before he dies.
但是他已经知道了
But he knows.
他现在知道我是什么人了
He knows what I am now.
他恨我
He hates me.
所以才叫考验啊
Well, that's what makes it a test.
如果你足够诡计多端  能赢回他的心
If you're guileful enough to win back his heart
足够残忍  能笑着看他被杀
and cruel enough to smile at his killing,
那我就知道家族的名号你当之无愧
then I'll know you're worthy of the family name.
哥哥  你不是吧
Brother, seriously?
饶了这可怜的孩子吧
Cut the poor kid some slack.
你还好意思说
More from you?
不是吧
Really?
没有别的办法考验我吗
Isn't there some other way?
亲爱的
Oh, my dear,
我非常喜欢你
I like you very much,
但是家族利益优先
but family interests come first,
杜马家族还有别的血脉能为我所用
and there are other girls of the Dumas blood I could turn to,
除非你能证明自己的能力
should you fail to prove your mettle.
明白了吗
Understand?
你真明白吗
Do you?
我亲爱的哥哥会把你扔到街上
My charming brother here will throw you out on the street,
如果他没对你痛下杀手的话
if he's kind enough not to kill you.
别往消极的方面想嘛
Well, let's not dwell on the negative, hmm?
你能行的
You can do it.
我知道你行的
I know you can.
要权变多谋  冷酷无情
Be resourceful, be ruthless.
你先去换件漂亮的衣服吧
Why don't you get yourself something pretty to put on.
你来做什么
Why are you here?
我想说
I wanted to say...
我真的
I'm really,
对发生的一切感到抱歉
really sorry for what's happened.
对骗你的事  我也很抱歉
And I'm sorry that I had to lie to you.
我必须照我叔叔说的做
I had to do what my uncle said.
但我觉得你是一个好人
But I think you're a good person,
如果我能帮你的话  我会帮的
and if I could help you, I would.
但是我不能  真抱歉
But I can't, and I'm sorry.
我觉得你或许想要人陪陪
And I thought maybe you would like some company.
如果你不需要  也没关系
But if you don't, that's fine,
我走
I'll go.
好
Yes.
请你离开吧
Please go.
你真的恨我吗
You really hate me?
我对你没有任何感觉
I have no feelings for you whatsoever.
我喜欢你
Well, I like you.
真对不起
And I'm sorry.
就是这样
That's all.
你想留下也可以
You can stay if you like.
抱歉
Excuse me.
停车  停车  停车
Stop, stop, stop!
停车  先生  停车  停车
Stop, sir! Stop, sir! Stop, stop, stop!
抱歉  先生
Excuse me, sir.
干什么  你是疯了吗
Oh, what, are you crazy or something?
停车
Stop!
别这样
Hey, come on!
别这样  我还要去上班呢
Come on, I got to get to work!
我真的非常抱歉  先生
I am most terribly sorry, sir.
我真的有非常紧急的事
I'm in the most frightful hurry.
别动
Freeze!
警官
Oh, Officers...
警监  怎么回事
Captain, what the hell?
你对吉姆下了通缉令吗
You put out a warrant on Jim?
哥谭市警局通缉
詹姆斯·戈登
持有武器  非常危险
"Armed and dangerous"?
没错
That's right.
他不是个罪犯
He's not a criminal.
他显然是被劫持了
He was obviously abducted
或是类似之类的
or-or-or something.
我希望你是对的
Look, I hope you're right,
但从现在的证据看却不是那样
but the facts on the ground don't look that way.
他袭击了市长
He assaulted the mayor
并和企鹅一起逃脱了哥谭市警局的拘捕
and escaped GCPD custody with Penguin.
两个好警察死了  而他还在逃
Two good cops died and now he's a fugitive.
不是犯罪  你把这叫做什么
What would you call that, if not criminal?
显然是盖勒文...
Well... Galavan was obviously...
除非有证据  盖勒文就是无辜的
Galavan is innocent until proven otherwise.
如果吉姆不是黑警
If Jim isn't dirty,
那他得自己来告诉我
I need to hear that from him.
他在哪  你知道吗
Where is he? Do you know where he is?
不知道
No.
你知道他和企鹅合作多久了吗
Do you know how long he's been working with Penguin?
他没有在和企鹅合作
He's not working with Penguin.
他也不是黑警
And he's not dirty,
我不喜欢这样被审问
and I resent being questioned like this.
得了吧  你是他女朋友
Oh, stop it. You're his girlfriend.
你知道我必问你这些问题
You know I have to ask you these questions.
我再问你一遍  你知不知道他在哪
I'm gonna ask you again if you know where he is,
因为如果你知道还不告诉我
because if you do, and you don't tell me,
那你就是事后从犯
that makes you an accomplice after the fact.
我不知道他在哪
I don't know where he is.
我也不想这么做
I don't like this any more than you do.
我把吉姆当亲儿子看待
Jim is like a son to me.
父亲对儿子该更信任些的
A father would have shown more faith.
你确定你真有自己想的那么了解吉姆吗
Are you sure you know Jim as well as you think you do?
你的爱人还活着吗
Is your lover-man alive?
去格伦迪街  805号
Go to Grundy. 805.
你跟我说两句话吧
Will you please talk to me?
沉默让我好难过
Silence makes me sad.
说什么
Talk about what?
无所谓
It doesn't matter.
什么都行
Anything.
前十榜什么的
Top ten lists...
最棒的度假
best vacations.
你最喜欢的动物是什么
What's your favorite animal?
猫头鹰
Owls.
猫头鹰  好吧
Owls, okay.
猫头鹰挺好的
Owls are cool.
你和海豚一起游过泳吗
Did you ever swim with a dolphin?
没有
No.
我游过一次
I did, once.
超棒的
Oh, my gosh.
简直有魔力
It was magical.
就像  我们是朋友  就像
It was... like we were friends, like...
它们有种魔力
They have this power.
能够读懂你的心
They can, like, read your mind.
它们不能
No, they can't.
他们可以的
No, they can.
他们可以看到你的脑电波
They can see your brain waves.
他们有类似声纳的系统
They have a form of sonar,
所以可以看透你  可以检测肿瘤之类的
so they can see inside you and detect tumors, that sort of thing.
但他们不会读心
But they can't read minds.
我见过的那只就可以
Well, the one I met could read my mind.
小莱
Lee.
你究竟在搞什么
What the hell are you doing?
我得安排你出城
I need to get you out of town.
企鹅认识个可靠的人  可以带你去州北
Penguin has a reliable man who can take you upstate.
这里会混乱一阵
Things are gonna be unsettled here for a while.
混乱
Unsettled?
我们要扳倒盖勒文
We're gonna take down Galavan.
你疯了吗
Are you out of your mind?
汤普金斯小姐  我向你保证...
Ms. Thompkins, I can assure you...
必须有人阻止他  小莱
He has to be stopped, Lee.
你吗
By you?
还有...这些人
And... these people?
必须有人阻止他
He has to be stopped.
你总是想自寻死路
You keep trying to kill yourself.
是我看错你了吗  你就是个疯子吗
Have I got you all wrong? Are you just crazy?
当然不是
Of course not.
你是个逃犯
You're on the run from the law.
你要让个道德败坏的反社会分子帮你袭击市长
You want to attack the mayor with the help of a depraved sociopath.
这还不叫疯狂吗
That's not crazy?
我听得见哦
I can hear you.
别说话
Don't speak.
吉姆  别这么做
Jim, don't do this.
咱们一起出城
Let's get out of town together.
我不在乎你做过什么
I don't care what you've done already
也不在乎你还有什么没做  我们走吧
or what you have to leave undone. Let's just go.
我不能走
I can't.
吉姆  拜托
Jim, please.
不行  我不能让盖勒文这么赢了
I can't. I can't let Galavan win this way.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
当时满屋子都是
There were silver-white roses
银白的玫瑰和红艳的百合
and red lilies all over the house.
我的朋友都在
All of my friends were there.
放着音乐  大家跳着舞
There was music and dancing.
我妈妈为我做了个蛋糕
And my mom made me a cake
上面还用巧克力写了我的名字
with my name spelled out in chocolate.
第二年  她就死了
That was the year before she died.
她当时好美
She looked so beautiful.
好高兴
And happy.
所以...
So, yeah...
...这是我最美好的回忆
...that's my favorite memory.
九岁生日
My ninth birthday.
你呢
How about you?
我不知道
I don't know.
说说嘛
Come on.
你肯定有
You must have one.
你父母真的死了  对吧
So your parents really are dead, are they?
对
Yeah.
这点我没说谎
I wasn't lying about that.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
演戏就是如此
That's show business.
有次我们去森林露营
We went camping once, in a forest.
我和我父亲爬到橡树上  吃橘子
My father and I climbed an oak tree and ate oranges.
我们能听到我妈一边哼着小曲  一边生火
We could hear my mom singing to herself as she built the fire.
那天很美好
That was a good day.
该死
Damn it...
该死  我不能这么做
Damn it. I can't do this.
我不能让你死
I can't let you die.
多谢你有这个心  但这事你能决定吗
That's good of you to say so, but is it up to you?
如果我们逃出牢房  越过守卫
If we can get out of the cell and past the guard,
我知道有个后楼梯无人看守
I know a back stairwell that isn't watched.
机会挺渺茫的
That's a big if.
你要怎么做
What are you going to do?
我毕竟是个杜马家的人
I am a Dumas.
我在这儿还是有点影响力的
I have some pull around here.
开门
Open up.
进来
Come in.
把你的枪给我
Give me your gun.
快跑
Come on!
你个傻姑娘
Oh, you silly girl.
你怎么想的啊
What were you thinking?
布鲁斯和阿尔弗雷德已经失踪至少12小时了
Bruce and Alfred have been gone for at least 12 hours.
他们恐怕是被劫持了
I'm afraid they've been abducted.
我们忙着呢  福克斯先生
We're very busy now, Mr. Fox.
12小时并不算久
12 hours isn't very long.
我确定是出事了
I am sure that something has happened.
一般来说失踪24小时以上
We usually don't post missing persons
才会给失踪立案
until they've been missing for 24 hours,
但出于对韦恩集团的尊敬
but out of respect for Wayne Enterprises...
布鲁斯·韦恩  阿尔弗雷德·潘尼沃斯
Bruce Wayne, Alfred Pennyworth.
在系统里查一下他们
Run them through the system.
谢谢
Thank you.
有任何绑架的证据吗
Was there any evidence of an abduction?
灯台被踢翻了
There was a lamp stand knocked over
一扇窗户敞着
and there was a window opened.
你觉得是谁绑架了他们
Who do you think abducted them?
西奥·盖勒文是最明显的嫌疑人
Well, Theo Galavan is the obvious suspect.
你有任何证据吗
Do you have any proof of that?
恐吓  物证
Uh... threats made, physical evidence?
没有
No.
但这多明显啊
But it's obvious.
他想夺走公司
He's trying to take over the company.
警监  我们知道他有问题
Captain, we know the man's dirty.
我们当然知道
Of course we know he's dirty.
哥谭的坏蛋我们都知道  又能如何
We know the names of every dirty crook in Gotham. So what?
证据啊  布洛克
Proof, Bullock! Proof!
要拿到针对盖勒文的逮捕令
To get a warrant against Galavan,
我们得能证明犯罪
we need proof of a crime
并能证明与他有关
and proof that he's involved.
说
Speak.
布鲁斯少爷在哪
Where's Master Bruce?
我们还希望你知道呢
We were hoping you knew.
我当时正在征用一辆车
I was in the process of commandeering a vehicle
你们两个白痴警察就
when two of your... idiotic cozzers shot me
用电击枪打中了我的脸
straight in the bloody face with a stun gun.
然后我就在这儿醒来了
Here I am.
这不就有逮捕令了吗  警监
And there's your warrant, Captain.
怎么说
Where?
他在盖勒文的地盘上
He was assaulted on Galavan's property
被盖勒文的已知同伙袭击了
by known associates of Galavan.
但他擅闯了盖勒文的塔楼
While trespassing in Galavan's Tower.
他是被居住者合法逐出了私人领地
He was lawfully pursued off the property by the rightful occupants.
这不算证据
You got nothing there.
是盖勒文抓了布鲁斯·韦恩  老大
Galavan's got Bruce Wayne, boss,
这错不了
sure as eggs.
拿出确凿证据来
Give me real proof.
我们已经对盖勒文操之过急一次了
We already jumped the gun once with Galavan
结果被坑惨了
and we got screwed.
没有确凿证据  不会有法官签发逮捕令的
Without solid proof, no judge is gonna sign a warrant.
不管你怎么说
.. eggs or no eggs.
那你说我们怎么办
So what do you propose we do?
你等着
You hang tight.
我们去找点
We'll dig up some...
健康安全方面的问题
health and safety issue.
想别的办法拿到针对盖勒文塔楼的搜查令
Get a backdoor warrant for Galavan Tower.
嗯  那得要多久
Right, how long's that gonna take, then?
大概得等到明早
Probably till tomorrow morning.
-但  -不可能更快了
- But... - That's the best we can do.
你可以走了
You're free to go.
我们会给你撤诉的
We'll drop your charges.
嗯  多谢
Right, well, you know, thank you
多谢了
very much indeed.
布洛克  我需要点干净绷带
Look, Bullock, I'm gonna need some clean bandages,
还需要辆车  几把枪
I'm gonna need a car... and a couple of guns.
没问题
You got it.
你要干什么
What are you going to do?
我没别的办法  也没时间了
I've got no choice. No time.
我得去找他
I've got to go visit him.
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
俩人够吗
Are two men enough?
虽然看上去不像  但我这人不擅用暴力
It wouldn't seem so, but violence is not my métier.
不  两个人是不够
No. Two men are not enough.
我很乐意加入你们  但我猜外行人也没什么用
I would gladly join you, but I imagine an amateur is no asset.
大概反会坏事
A hindrance, perhaps.
是的  我们需要吉姆·戈登
That's very true. We need Jim Gordon.
他最适合干这种事了
He's perfect for this kind of thing.
他在哪呢
Where is he?
是啊  吉姆·戈登在哪
Yeah, where is Jim Gordon?
说来话长  没人知道
It's a long story, but nobody knows.
好笑吗  爱德
Something funny, Ed?
你知道戈登在哪吗
Do you know where Gordon is?
你知道吗
Do you?
说话  四眼
Start speaking, Windows.
花钢板  亮格栅  寸步不离  我在哪
A diamond plate, a glowing grate, a place you never leave. Where am I?
什么
What?
家
Home.
谁的家  你家吗
Whose home? Your home?
戈登在你家
Gordon's at your home?
不...是的
N... No. Yes.
你是谁
Who are you?
祝你好运  老朋友
Good luck, old friend.
回头见
See you around.
希望不见
I hope not.
再见了  企鹅
Good-bye, Penguin.
再见  汤普金斯小姐
Good-bye, Ms. Thompkins.
请别把我想的太坏
Please don't think too badly of me.
我们是什么人无法改变
We are what we are.
是啊
That's true.
再见了  科波特先生
Good-bye, Mr. Cobblepot.
我们走吧
Let's go.
嗯
Yeah.
等着我
Wait here.
盖勒文抓了布鲁斯
Galavan has Bruce.
我明白
I understand.
保证我
Just promise me...
什么
What?
算了
Never mind.
做你觉得该做的
Do what you think is best.
都结束了来找我
Call me when it's over.
我一定很狼狈吧
I must look terrible.
不  没有
No. You don't.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好冷静啊
You're so calm.
就好像你根本不怕
It's like you're not scared.
我想我是不怕
I guess I'm not.
好奇怪
It's weird.
你...才奇怪
You... are weird.
但我爱你
But I love you.
是吗
Do you?
是的
I do.
你爱我吗
Do you love me?
不
No.
No?
茜尔薇  我不知道你为什么这么做
Silver, I don't know why you're doing it,
但我知道你在玩弄我
but I know you're playing with me.
我知道逃跑就是一出戏
I know that whole escape was a ghoulish charade.
不是那样的
That's a horrible lie.
我跟你说这话是因为  等我死了
I'm only telling you this because, when I'm dead,
你可能会觉得内疚
you may feel bad,
我不希望你觉得你骗了我
and I don't want you to think you tricked me.
茜尔薇  我不爱你
Silver, I don't love you.
我同情你
I pity you.
你为什么这么做
Why do you do this?
有什么意义
What's the point?
西奥叔叔逼我的
Uncle Theo made me.
他说如果我不能让你再爱上我
He said if I can't make you love me again,
如果你不跟我吻别
if you don't kiss me good-bye,
那我就不配做这家人
then I'm not good enough for the family.
他就会赶走我
He's going to kick me out.
或者杀了我
Or kill me.
其实没区别
Same thing, really.
我明白了
I see.
天呐  我真没用
God, I'm such a loser.
邪恶  可悲  没用
An evil, pathetic loser.
不是的
You're not.
你是年轻  害怕
You're young and scared
被恶人控制了
and under the control of bad people.
你可以改变
You can change.
还有希望
There's hope.
你无法想象
You can't even imagine
我都做过什么
the things I've done.
没有希望了
There's no hope.
我回不去正常生活了
There's no going back to normal life.
我的家族就是我的一切
My family is all I have.
现在我连他们也失去了
Now I've lost them, too.
好了
All right.
大家准备好了吗  我们走吧
Everybody set? Let's go.
什么计划
What's the plan?
我们冲进大楼  找到盖勒文
We get into that building, find Galavan,
拿枪逼着他说出布鲁斯在哪
put a gun in his mouth until he gives up Bruce.
然后我慢慢杀了他
Then I kill him slowly.
不行  然后我们逮捕他
No. Then we arrest him.
不行
Yeah, no.
你疯了吗
Are you nuts?
他做了那么多恶事
After all that he has done?
他要接受审判
He's going to stand trial.
得让哥谭知道他的真面目
Gotham needs to know who he really is.
哥谭需要他死
Gotham needs him dead!
吵吵吵
Rabbit, rabbit, rabbit.
能不能先别吵了  赶紧冲进去再说啊
Can we just stop the bunny and just first get in there, please,
各位
chaps?
是啊  我们走吧
Yes. Let's go.
说真的  就这样吗  你毫无计划吗
Seriously, that's it? You have no plan?
你打算怎么进去啊
How are you even going to get into the building?
我知道条路
I know a way.
她是谁
Who is she?
福克斯  这是小猫
Fox, that's Cat.
小猫  这是福克斯
Cat, Fox.
-你知道进去的路  -是的
- You know a way in? - Yeah.
我知道进去的路  戈登
I know a way in, Gordon.
我们怎么知道你不是在给我们下套
How do we know you haven't stitched us up?
你可经常换边站
I mean, you've switched sides often enough.
我们怎么知道你现在不是给盖勒文卖命了
How do we know that you're not working with Galavan now?
我怎么知道你不是穿橡皮衣的火星人
How do I know you're not a Martian in a rubber suit?
我信任她
I trust her.
你可以加入  小猫
You're in, Cat.
多谢帮忙
Thanks for your help.
拿件防弹衣  我们走吧
Grab a vest and let's go.
各位  我们总得准备个后备方案
People, surely we should have a backup strategy,
鉴于失败的可能性如此之大
given the strong possibilities of failure.
恰恰相反  福克斯先生
Au contraire, Mr. Fox.
失败是不可以的
Failure is not an option!
他说的没错
What he said.
好吧
As you like.
别装作你不害怕了
Stop acting like you're not scared.
我知道你是怕的
I know you are.
当然
Sure.
或许有点吧
Maybe a little but...
但我更多是觉得很鲜活
mostly, I feel very alive.
甚至开心
Happy, even.
我要见到我父母了
I'm going to see my parents.
先别急
Hold that thought.
好戏开始了
Showtime.
稍等一下
One moment, please.
再见  茜尔薇
Good-bye, Silver.
我爱你
I love you.
我原谅你
And I forgive you.
好样的
Bravo.
进来吧
Come on in.
老天爷啊
Oh, for Pete's sake.
死神降临哥谭之子  死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham. Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子  死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham. Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子  死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham. Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham.
-怎么回事啊  -死神降临哥谭之子
- What in the hell is that? - Death to the Son of Gotham.
-绝不是好事  -死神降临哥谭之子
- Nothing good. - Death to the Son of Gotham.
-我就上去  -死神降临哥谭之子
- I'll be right there. - Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子  死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham. Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子
Death to the Son of Gotham.
死神降临哥谭之子  死神...
Death to the Son of Gotham. Death...
准备好  孩子
Prepare yourself, boy.
你是个痴心妄想的老傻瓜
You're a deluded, old fool.
你会为此付出代价的
And you'll pay for this.
祖先们
Ancestors,
请为我们见证
be our witness.
预言将实现
The prophecy is fulfilled.
住手
Stop!
求你
Please?
亵渎
Sacrilege.
听好...稍等一下
Listen to me very... Hold on just a moment.
好吧  福克斯先生  快点说  什么事
All right, Mr. Fox, make it quick, what do you got?
我知道詹姆斯·戈登现在在哪
I have the current location of James Gordon.
我待会儿打给你
I'll call you back.
放下刀  老头子  结束了
Drop the knife, old man. It's over.
看来是的
So it would seem.
好多的楼梯啊
That was a lot of stairs.
你没事吧
You all right?
盖勒文呢
Where's Galavan?
现在只有一条出路了
Only one way out of here now...
-往下走  -只有两个啊
- straight down. - There's only two of them.
茜尔薇不跟我们走了
Silver isn't coming.
亲爱的  我只想花点时间
I just wanted to take a moment,
表达我对你
sweetheart, to express my deep...
-深深的失望  -西奥  放过她吧
- disappointment in you. - Theo, leave her be.
闭嘴
Silence!
去死吧
Bite me.
什么
What...
你在做什么
what are you doing?
我都不认识你了
I don't know who you are anymore.
得了  这话太老套了
Oh, please, that is such a ridiculous cliché...
够了  哥哥  你输了
Forget it, brother. You lost.
我该照顾好自己了
It's time for me to look out for number one.
抱歉
Sorry.
塔比莎
Tabitha!
西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
天呐
Oh, God.
你吓死我了  我以为你要开枪呢
you scared me, man. I thought you were gonna shoot me.
自己铐上
Cuff yourself.
谢天谢地
Well, thank goodness for...
这世上有你这种守原则的简单人
simple men of principle.
相信体制
Who believe in the system.
你这次会上电椅的
This time you'll get the chair.
想打赌吗
You want to make a bet?
或许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
别冲动  吉姆  我就是在吹牛
Steady now, Jim. I was just talking big,
就如人所说
as they say.
你光明正大地逮到了我
You caught me fair and square.
上次就是如此
Had you that way the last time.
你还是扭转了局势
You turned it around.
吉姆
Jim.
退后
Back up.
有我呢
I got him.
我叫你退后
Back up, I said.
你  跪下
And you-- on your knees.
我有搜查这里的搜查令
I have a warrant to search these premises.
吉姆
Jim,
你把枪放地上
now, you put your gun on the ground
手放在头后
and put your hands on top of your head.
-什么  -没错  你还是个逃犯呢
- What? - You heard me. You're still a fugitive.
警监  我没做错事
Captain, I've done nothing wrong.
我也想相信你  吉姆
I want to believe you, Jim.
所以我们得照规矩来
So we're gonna do this by the book.
你把枪放地上
Put your gun on the ground
我们好好处理这事
and let's handle this the right way.
你在犯错误
You're making a mistake.
别开枪
Nobody shoot--
我们都是朋友
we are all friends here.
才不是
Like hell we are.
这事我抱歉
I apologize for that.
但是现在好了
But there we are. Done now.
他们还活着  这不挺好
They're still alive. That's something.
往前看  吉姆  现在怎么办
Look forward now, Jim. What now?
如果实在不行  我会杀了你再杀他
I will kill you to get to him if I have to.
不说这男人让芭芭拉·基恩去杀你
Forget that this man sicced Barbara Kean on you.
不说他险些杀了你孩子的母亲
Forget that he nearly killed the mother of your child.
不说复仇  单想想大局
Forget revenge. Think of the greater good.
想想哥谭
Think of Gotham.
他收买了法院
He has the courts in his pocket
有数十亿元可以支配
and billions of dollars at his command.
你真的确定
Are you 100% sure that
他不会再次逍遥法外吗
he won't beat this and walk free again?
你确定吗  吉姆
Are you sure, Jim?
想想哥谭啊
Think of Gotham.
警监  B队靠近顶层公寓了
Captain, Bravo Team in the vicinity of the penthouse.
快点想
But think fast.
我相信  布鲁斯少爷
I do believe, Master Bruce,
这绝对可以算是
this falls very firmly
"我早说过"的那种事
into the category of "I told you so".
我也早说过了  阿尔弗雷德
I told him so, too, Alfred.
是的  谢谢你们的帮助
Yes, well, thank you both for your help,
但我本来有个非常可行的逃跑计划
but I had a perfectly feasible escape plan.
你是个有良心的人  吉姆  你会后悔的
You're a man of conscience, Jim. You'll regret this.
我有很多后悔
I have many regrets.
这件事不会占榜首的
This won't be top of the list.
好了
Now, uh...
这一刻来了
here we are.
遗憾啊
Shame.
明天将是个美丽的早晨
It's gonna be a beautiful morning.
再见了  吉姆·戈登
Good-bye, Jim Gordon.
这是为了我母亲
This is for my mother.
杀了我吧  求你
Kill me, please. Please.
够了
Enough!
That's enough.
结束了
It's over.
-真的吗  -是的
- Is it? - Yes.
很好
Good.
你愿意嫁给我吗
Will you marry me?
印第安山
有毒废料倾倒场
不得进入
哥谭市法医部
给你  皮博迪女士
Here you go, Ms. Peabody.
市停尸房来的鲜肉
Fresh meat from the city morgue.
放尊重点
Show some respect.
斯特兰奇教授对他抱有很大希望呢
Professor Strange has high hopes for this one.
这倒是新鲜
That's unusual.